<item>
	<title>One Last Song interview at Silver Bullet Comics</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2007/02/22/one-last-song-interview-at-silver-bullet-comics</link>
	<pubDate>Thu Feb 22 23:00:41 -0800 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="onelastsong"><![CDATA[onelastsong]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2007/02/22/one-last-song-interview-at-silver-bullet-comics</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote class="posterous_medium_quote">Love is all you need… especially if you plan to use pop music to topple a dystopian government in the year 2049, as the protagonist of writer CJ Hurtt and artist Shawn Richter’s One Last Song intends to.

Set to drop in April, One Last Song is a new series from Brain Scan Studios focusing on Amanda Casey—a pop musician adding subtly subversive messages to her commercially acceptable music in order to combat a dystopian regime. Like any good oppressive government, the bureaucrats of One Last Song have cracked down on free expression, and given American entertainers a choice: carry an officially sanctioned “performance card” or be quietly shuffled off to a “terror aversion camp.” </blockquote>

Check out the interview in it's <a href="http://www.silverbulletcomics.com/news/story.php?a=4087">entirety over at Silver Bullet Comics</a>.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Love is all you need… especially if you plan to use pop music to topple a dystopian government in the year 2049, as the protagonist of writer CJ Hurtt and artist Shawn Richter’s One Last Song intends to. Set to drop in April, One Last Song is a ne...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Thu Feb 22 23:00:41 -0800 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2007/02/22/one-last-song-interview-at-silver-bullet-comics</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
