<item>
	<title>Hellboy and the Comic Shop</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2004/03/31/hellboy-and-the-comic-shop</link>
	<pubDate>Wed Mar 31 18:25:19 -0800 2004</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="ranting"><![CDATA[ranting]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2004/03/31/hellboy-and-the-comic-shop</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[Got some free tickets to see <a href="http://www.sonypictures.com/movies/hellboy/">Hellboy</a> last night, so I picked up my brother and we headed over to the movie theater that was showing it. Sadly we ended up being a bit late (a habit of mine), and the line for entrance was winding around the theater. Being hungry and not in the mood to wait in line only to find out that we couldn't enter we decided on hitting the nearby mall for some food and to wander around the mall.
<!--more-->
For all of you living in the Orlando area, the <a href="http://www.coliseumofcomics.com/">Coliseum of Comics</a> is moving upstairs to newer and I guess more glamourous digs. Just a public service announcement for those in Orlando. Anywhoo while we were there I picked up <a href="http://www.dccomics.com/graphic_novels/ws_display.html?cat=wildstorm&amp;itemCode=authtop">The Authority: Transfer of Power</a> graphic novel, even though I have the floppies for that set of books I hate having to hunt through my long boxes to find them. I also picked up Steve Rude's <a href="http://www.darkhorse.com/profile/profile.php?sku=13-148">The Moth</a> (haven't read yet) and <a href="http://www.avatarpress.com/theunfunnies/">The Unfunnies #2</a> (just read).

The Unfunnies #2 (a review)
I picked this up because I picked up #1 and although #1 was humorous I didn't get a whole lot out of it. I really didn't know if this was an excuse for Millar to curse a whole lot and force cartoon character's into sexual situtions that in some cases are just plain disturbing. Well #2 changed that for me.
First off, this is an adult comic, those with weak stomachs and are a bit more conservative might have some issues with this series. But it's quite funny to me that the more mature readers comics that I normally read go nowhere near the limits that this series does. And in reality this series is no more bad than the "R-ist" of R-movies (ok there are some scenes in this series that would have serious trouble getting passed the MPAA). I really don't know where I was going with that last thought, maybe I'm saying that the "mature readers" label on that book should be that, for mature readers, the same stuff you can say/do in "Pulp Fiction" should be dropped into that book, or maybe I just want more cartoon characters cursing.
Anyway Millar continues his series with more hijinks in the cartoon world he's setup in the first issue, he touches on a mother being offered an abortion for her 10 year trouble causing daughter to a baby chick being shot in the head. Again without giving too much away, no punches are pulled. And at the end of this story I felt there was a point, there is a plot being woven in and out of all this madness, it's not just cartoon characters cursing and having sex. So do I recommend it? Well, Millar's intrigued me enough to buy the third issue and that's enough for me.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Got some free tickets to see Hellboy last night, so I picked up my brother and we headed over to the movie theater that was showing it. Sadly we ended up being a bit late (a habit of mine), and the line for entrance was winding around the theater....]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Wed Mar 31 18:25:19 -0800 2004</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2004/03/31/hellboy-and-the-comic-shop</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
