<item>
	<title>Some neat links</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2005/06/21/some-neat-links-2</link>
	<pubDate>Tue Jun 21 18:01:31 -0700 2005</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="ranting"><![CDATA[ranting]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2005/06/21/some-neat-links-2</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.kottke.org/05/05/ajax-weblogs">Ajax and weblogs</a> - Kottke talking about adding an Ajax menu (he's since removed) on his blog. Nice set of notes on how he did it.

<a href="http://www.boingboing.net/2005/05/11/obscure_disneyland_f.html">Obscure Disneyland factoids</a> - Fifty odd facts about the Disneyland park.

<a href="http://www.boingboing.net/2005/05/11/manga_head_styling_g.html">Manga Head styling gel </a> - This link is for my brother Marc.

<a href="http://www.dailykos.com/storyonly/2005/5/14/145422/330">Microsoft in Cell phones</a> - Nice little op/ed on why Microsoft should stay out of the cellphone business.

<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/archive/max-blumenthal/is-yoga-the-devils-subte.html">Is Yoga The Devil's Subterfuge?</a> - There are people (a group of Christians, what a shock!) who believe that yoga is evil. What the hell is wrong with these people?

<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/theblog/archive/pat-morrison/creationism-v-evolution-.html">Creationism v. Evolution -- Leave it to the Beavers</a> - From the article: "My favorite moment in sci vs. fi history was when the JPL launched the Cassini space probe of Saturn in 1997. Soon after, the JPL phone rang; attorneys for clothes designer Oleg Cassini were demanding to know how JPL had the effrontery to name a space probe after the man who designed ensembles for Jackie Kennedy and almost married Grace Kelly]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Ajax and weblogs - Kottke talking about adding an Ajax menu (he's since removed) on his blog. Nice set of notes on how he did it. Obscure Disneyland factoids - Fifty odd facts about the Disneyland park. Manga Head styling gel - This link is for my...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Tue Jun 21 18:01:31 -0700 2005</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2005/06/21/some-neat-links-2</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
