<item>
	<title>Triumphant return and some reviews</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2004/04/27/triumphant-return-and-some-reviews</link>
	<pubDate>Tue Apr 27 08:55:02 -0700 2004</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="ranting"><![CDATA[ranting]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2004/04/27/triumphant-return-and-some-reviews</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[First off I swear I will continue to regale everyone with stories of the honeymoon, but here are some reviews I was going to do prior the whole madness of getting married. Oh and obviously me and my beautiful bride have returned from California. You know what sucks about returning from California to Florida? First thing, is the humidity here in Florida, where the hell did all this moisture come from? The other thing is the fact that it's midnight and it feels like nine o'clock, it's going to be a late night. Anyway here are some reviews. Oh and to warn you folks the second review will be "adult" in nature.
<!--more-->
<a href="http://www.dccomics.com/comics/vt_display.html?cm_vt_itemCode=biteclub1&amp;month=April">Fight Club #1</a> Howard Chaykin &amp; David Tischman - Writers, David Hahn Artist
It's "The Godfather" meets vampires, absolutely wonderful, my only complaint is that I'm not a big fan of "cartoon-ey" art. The story is about a mob-vampire boss who mysteriously dies and all the expected turmoil afterwards. The entire family must return and although it's not shown in the first issue, you can feel there will be a big showdown to tear apart the old man's empire. Highly recommended.

New X-Men #155 Chuck Austen - Writer, Salvador Larroca - Artist
Crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap, crap. I got tired of pasting the word "crap". Marvel, can't you have just taken 24 pictures of Chuck Austen taking a shit on a stack of the entire run of Morrison's New X-Men? Wouldn't that have been easier than paying an artist, letterer, etc? Nice work on ruining it for me guys. Take a bow. Wouldn't recommend to anyone.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[First off I swear I will continue to regale everyone with stories of the honeymoon, but here are some reviews I was going to do prior the whole madness of getting married. Oh and obviously me and my beautiful bride have returned from California. Y...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Tue Apr 27 08:55:02 -0700 2004</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2004/04/27/triumphant-return-and-some-reviews</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
