<item>
	<title>What comics guys talk about over dinner.</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2006/04/10/what-comics-guys-talk-about-over-dinner</link>
	<pubDate>Mon Apr 10 20:27:06 -0700 2006</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="interestinglinks"><![CDATA[interestinglinks]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2006/04/10/what-comics-guys-talk-about-over-dinner</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[From Wired - <a href="http://www.blogbuzzmachine.com/subs/subscribe.php?id=751248">Subscribe to the Wired Blog via Blog Buzz Machine</a>:

'Around midnight, in a Japanese bar in New York's East Village, the science fiction writer Neil Gaiman is pouring himself a shot of sake. It's the table's second bottle, part of a dinner that got started late because nearly every one of the 400 or so audience members at a talk Gaiman gave earlier tonight brought something for him to autograph - his novel Anansi Boys, DVDs of his BBC series Neverwhere, copies of his graphic novel Sandman. Wherever Gaiman appears, geeks of every stripe turn out in droves: beautiful goth girls with oil-black hair and cherry-red lips, overweight comics nerds (with dates), underweight comics nerds (with dates), science fiction obsessives, manga fanatics.

It's a fiercely dedicated fan base. "Do you know that paperback editions of Sandman actually sell better each year than the previous year?" Gaiman says. It's a shock. The book is 15 years old.

"Then I have a question for you," says another member of the party, Mitch Cutler, owner of St. Marks Comics. Located just around the corner, it's one of the country's best independent comic book retail shops. "Who do you think the next generation of readers will be?"

This is what comics guys talk about over dinner: What happens when 14-year-old boys put down their tales of garishly clad, overmuscled men who like to bash robots? "I'm not sure," Gaiman says. "But I do know that when I got to Singapore to do a reading, there were 600 teenage girls waiting. And when I got to the Philippines, there were 2,000 teenage girls waiting, screaming my name."

Cutler nods. "That's it," he says. "It's girls between 13 and 25."'

Read the whole <a href="http://www.wired.com/wired/archive/14.04/posts.html?pg=6">article</a>.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[From Wired - Subscribe to the Wired Blog via Blog Buzz Machine: 'Around midnight, in a Japanese bar in New York's East Village, the science fiction writer Neil Gaiman is pouring himself a shot of sake. It's the table's second bottle, part of a din...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Mon Apr 10 20:27:06 -0700 2006</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2006/04/10/what-comics-guys-talk-about-over-dinner</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
