<item>
	<title>Gordon Ramsay’s Scrambled Eggs</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2007/06/04/gordon-ramsays-scrambled-eggs</link>
	<pubDate>Mon Jun 04 18:43:58 -0700 2007</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="cooking"><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="food"><![CDATA[food]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2007/06/04/gordon-ramsays-scrambled-eggs</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[I came across this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=C1SM73Qi1BQ">video</a> the other day, claiming it shows the secret of cooking the best scrambled eggs you've ever tasted.

<object height="350" width="425"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/C1SM73Qi1BQ" />
<param name="wmode" value="transparent" />
<embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/C1SM73Qi1BQ" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" wmode="transparent" height="350" width="425"></embed></object>

The video (for those of you without the patience to watch it) shows <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gordon_Ramsay">Gordon Ramsay's</a> version of scrambled eggs. Now the man has several TV shows, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2Fs%3Fie%3DUTF8%26rs%3D%26keywords%3Dgordon%2520ramsay%26rh%3Di%253Aaps%252Ck%253Agordon%2520ramsay%252Ci%253Astripbooks&amp;tag=urbanossurfshop&amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325">written books</a>, and has several <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michelin_Guide">Michelin starred</a> <a href="http://www.gordonramsay.com/ukrestaurants/">restaurants</a> so I figured he might know what he's talking about.
The concept is fairly easy. For my lovely wife and myself, I dropped four (4) cold eggs, and two (2) tbsp of butter (cold) into a cold pot. I turned my stove top to 3 1/2 (low but not too low, my stove's low setting is "2") and placed the pot on top. Here's where it gets strenuous, the direction you'll be taking is roughly the same as risotto. Stir, stir and  more stirring. Every several minutes I took the eggs of the heat, continuing to stir. The eggs take on a pearl shaped porridge feel, I'm going to say the whole thing (stirring, move from the heat, move back to the heat, etc.) took about ten minutes. What you're looking for is about 75% firm, 25% runny eggs. Take the eggs off the heat but continue to stir, allowing the residual heat to "tighten up" the eggs. Sadly I didn't have any <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cr%C3%A8me_fra%C3%AEche">Crème fraîche</a> so I added one (1) tbsp of half-and-half and stirred like a man possessed. I seasoned the eggs with 2 pinches of salt, and a big grind of pepper. Since I had two tortillas available I served the eggs on the tortillas and topped with salsa and shredded cheddar cheese.

Things I would have done different:
- Try adding the crème fraîche and scallions like Ramsay recommends. Also serve as recommended on sour dough toast (mmm boy) with tomatoes on the vine and portobello mushroom tops.
- Much less salsa, we lost the taste of the eggs because of the salsa topping. They eggs were excellent though.]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I came across this video the other day, claiming it shows the secret of cooking the best scrambled eggs you've ever tasted. The video (for those of you without the patience to watch it) shows Gordon Ramsay's version of scrambled eggs. Now the man ...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Mon Jun 04 18:43:58 -0700 2007</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2007/06/04/gordon-ramsays-scrambled-eggs</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
