<item>
	<title>Brain Scan Studios to publish Rich Johnston’s Civil Wardrobe</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2006/07/13/brain-scan-studios-to-publish-rich-johnstons-civil-wardrobe</link>
	<pubDate>Thu Jul 13 19:40:42 -0700 2006</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="projects"><![CDATA[projects]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2006/07/13/brain-scan-studios-to-publish-rich-johnstons-civil-wardrobe</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<strong>Civil Wardrobe a parody comic book from writer Rich Johnston with art from Kaare Andrews, Ashley Wood, Darick Robertson and more!</strong>

THE DESIGN SENSE OF THE UNIVERSE IS CHANGING AND IT'S TIME TO DECIDE: WHOSE SIDE DO YOU DRESS ON?

Rich Johnston, star of CSI: Dying In The Gutters, and gossip monger extraordinaire has assembled an awesome army of artists (Kaare Andrews, Ashley Wood, Darick Robertson, Ilya, Fred Hembeck, Billy Dallas Patton, Mike Netzer, Lea Hernandez, Frazer Irving, Natalie Sandalls, Sam Hart, Thomas Mauer and more) to portray a changing universe in conflict. As The Old Fanboy Warriors die in an explosion and the battle over the Deconstruction Act begins, so some very familiar figures are redesigned, revamped and reconstructed, from Spider-Mart to Osama Bin Hulk. Joe Quesada has officially not objected to the publication of this one shot. And there is no Mike Turner variant cover. Sorry.

Published this October by Brain Scan Studios, available in August's Previews.
$3.50 24 pages

For more information please visit the official <a href="http://www.civil-wardrobe.com/">Civil Wardrobe website</a>.

Also be sure to add <a href="http://www.myspace.com/civilwardrobe">Civil Wardrobe</a> to your MySpace friend's list!]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Civil Wardrobe a parody comic book from writer Rich Johnston with art from Kaare Andrews, Ashley Wood, Darick Robertson and more! THE DESIGN SENSE OF THE UNIVERSE IS CHANGING AND IT'S TIME TO DECIDE: WHOSE SIDE DO YOU DRESS ON? Rich Johnston, star...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Thu Jul 13 19:40:42 -0700 2006</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2006/07/13/brain-scan-studios-to-publish-rich-johnstons-civil-wardrobe</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
