<item>
	<title>World’s largest mall</title>
	<link>http://www.briankirsten.com/2005/05/04/worlds-largest-mall</link>
	<pubDate>Wed May 04 20:10:27 -0700 2005</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brian Kirsten]]></dc:creator>
	
	
		<category domain="tag" nicename="ranting"><![CDATA[ranting]]></category>
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.briankirsten.com/2005/05/04/worlds-largest-mall</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[I don't know if this is really sad or not, but the screaming American consumer in me is ready to travel halfway around the world to see the biggest friggen mall in the World.

From the article:
"It takes about two days to explore Beijing's new Golden Resources Shopping Mall - the world's largest. Minnesota's "Mall of America" is 4 million square feet. Golden Resources, built in an impressive 20 months and opened Oct. 24, is 6 million square feet."

"Malls, those US-derived temples of consumerism, were once nonexistent in communist China. But they mushroom so fast today that even Premier Wen Jiabao warned this summer of a shopping mall craze."

"The observable problem with new shopping malls in China, however, is that they have few shoppers. While Golden officials first estimated 50,000 people a day, only a tiny fraction of that figure can be seen."

<a href="http://www.csmonitor.com/2004/1124/p01s03-woap.html">Read the full article</a>.

(Link courtesy of <a href="http://www.christinekirsten.com">Christine</a>)]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[I don't know if this is really sad or not, but the screaming American consumer in me is ready to travel halfway around the world to see the biggest friggen mall in the World. From the article: "It takes about two days to explore Beijing's new Gold...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Wed May 04 20:10:27 -0700 2005</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>2005/05/04/worlds-largest-mall</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
